Guide to the Hayne Family Papers1903-2015
Montana State University Library, Archives and Special Collections, Manuscript Collections
Hayne Family papers
1903-2015
Montana State University Library, Archives and Special Collections, Manuscript Collections
Hayne Family
2622
14.2 linear feet
The Hayne family papers consist of Jack Hayne's research files, records of the Dupuyer Social Club and community, Harriet's political papers, family correspondence, family personal papers, photograph and scrapbook albums, and loose photographs.
Harriet Ann Danielsen Hayne and Jack McVicar Hayne have had a huge impact on Montana's Dupuyer community since they moved there from Seattle in 1953. The seventh child born to Norwegian immigrants Angeline and Albert Danielsen, Harriett was born on September 11th, 1922 on Puget Island in Washington. Her siblings were named Ben, Dan, Elmer, Adine, Inga, and Palmer. After growing up on Puget Island, she decided to attend Heald College in San Francisco in 1940. Following the United States entrance into World War II and the creation of the Marine Corps Women's Reserve in 1943, Harriet left Heald and joined the Women's Reserve. While serving in the Reserve, she met Jack Hayne, who was serving in the Navy as an officer.
Jack Hayne, born in Great Falls, Montana on November 22, 1920, was one of two children of George Roy and Effie McVicar Hayne. His father Roy served in World War I and was a homesteader in Teton County. Jack's sister was named Margaret Sue. When the U.S. entered World War II, Jack enlisted in the U.S. Navy and served for the duration of the conflict. On April 3, 1946, he married Harriet in New Orleans. The couple moved to Seattle to attend Washington State University. Completing their studies, the Haynes then moved to Dupuyer, Montana where they established a farm and permanent residence. Harriett got involved with Montana politics and community affairs, becoming a state representative for the Republican Party and accumulating almost twenty years of political experience. Jack took an interest in the history of the West and Montana. His studying and research of Montana history would lead to his appointment to the Montana Historical Society board of trustees. Jack and Harriett had four children: Mary, John, Ali and Nancy. Harriett passed away in February 2012. Jack passed away in February 2018.
The Hayne family papers consist of Jack Hayne's research files, records of the Dupuyer Social Club and community, Harriet's political papers, family correspondence, family personal papers, photograph and scrapbook albums, and loose photographs. The collection has been divided into series reflecting these divisions.
Series 1 Research Files
Series 2 Dupuyer Social Club
Series 3 Political Papers
Series 4 Correspondence, 1903-2012
Series 5 Personal Papers
Series 6 Photographs, Albums, and Ephemra
This collection is open for research.
Research files, correspondence, memorabilia, photographs and other papers created or collected by the Jack and Harriet Hayne family of Dupuyer, Montana were purchased by the Montana State University Library from Jack Hayne on April 6, 2017.
Montana
Women; Clubs; Railroads
Architecture; Clubs and Societies; Elementary and Secondary Education; Fisheries and Wildlife; Home and Family; Military; Native Americans; Politics and Politicians; Railroads; Sports and Recreation; Transportation; Idaho; Montana; Oregon; Wyoming; Maps; Scrapbooks; Architecture; Women; Photographs
Photographs; Photographs; Photographs; Scrapbooks
- Research Files, 1
  After arriving in Dupuyer, Jack Hayne took on the role of historian by diving into and researching a multitude of subjects relating to Montana and the West. He liked to focus on the towns and events in Montana: The Baker Massacre, Dupuyer, Conrad, Montana and Alberta based railroads, and other topics. These papers consist of the materials he collected during his research on those topics: Newspapers, photos, magazine articles, letters and documents. Photos related to this series are numbers: 1-72.
  - Acantha Publishers (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Acquisition of the soil of Montana (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Agawam (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Alderich, Frank – Little Rockies Gold Rush (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Altyn (Box 1, Folder 5)
    [AM Ester]
  - Anaconda, Montana (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Arnoux, James (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Aznde – Genou (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Background on county development in western Montana (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Badger Agency (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Bair Mansion – Martinsdale (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Baker Massacre – Anniversary of the Baker Massacre (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Baker Massacre – Baker Site Meeting (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Baker Massacre – Bradley Papers, Prelude to the Massacre (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Baker Massacre – Correspondences (Box 1, Folder 15-16)
    (Miscellaneous)
  - Baker Massacre – Correspondences with Stan Gibson (Box 1, Folder 17-25)
  - Baker Massacre – The Dead Indian Coulee (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Baker Massacre – Gary Montgomery (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Baker Massacre – Heavy Runner Claim (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Baker Massacre – Horace Clark Interview (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Baker Massacre – Indian Battles and skirmishes on the American frontier, (1790-1898) (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Baker Massacre – Indian-White relations (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Baker Massacre – Legal Description of Baker site (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Baker Massacre – Materials (Box 1, Folder 33-36)
  - Baker Massacre – The Manas massacre Site: A progress report (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Baker Massacre – Missing Parts: Notes on a Massacre (Box 1, Folder 38-39)
  - Baker Massacre – Montana Magazine (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Baker Massacre – Muster Rolls (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Baker Massacre – Newspaper Articles, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Baker Massacre – News Stories, State Newspapers, 1870 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Baker Massacre – Notes on an Obscure Massacre (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Baker Massacre – Piegan War, of 1870 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Baker Massacre – Ponsford (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Baker Massacre – Robert Murry, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Baker Massacre – "Which way to the local battlefield?" (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Baker Massacre – Wischmann Story on Culbertson (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Baker Massacre – Witnesses to Carnage (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Bannack (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Barbed Wire (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Barber (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Barn Again, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Barns – Newspaper Stories (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Barns – Photos (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Bartlett, Montana (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Beaverhead County (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Beaver Slide Saloon (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Beaver Slide Stacker (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Bee's Honey (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Belt, Montana (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Big Horn County (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Biodiesel (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Birch Creek Hanging, 1885 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Bitterroot County Purposed, 1800s (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Blackfeet Agency Headquarters, Badger Creek (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Blackfeet (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Blackfeet Reservation Reports, (1889-1891) (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Blackfeet reservation boundary changes (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Blackfeet Reservation Report, 1894 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Blackfeet Water Rights (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Blaine County (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Bogus Legislatures (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Boone and Crockett, Grizzly Bears, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Boundaries – Early Day Wyoming, Idaho, Montana (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Brady, Montana (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Broadwater County (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - The Buffalo Hunt (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Buffalo in Yellowstone – control (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Buffalo Jump – Head Smashed In (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Bull Teams (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Burton, Burtonville, Montana (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Bynum Bank (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Bynum, Dupuyer, Robare, during the year 1889 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Bynum, Montana (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Bynum Train, Bynum Reservoir (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Camas Bulbs (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Carbon County (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - The Carroll Trail (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Carter County (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Cascade County (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Cascade, Montana (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Cattle Drives, West's 1st, Montana Centennial (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Cattle Mutilations in Dupuyer (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Cattle Queen of Montana, Mrs. Nat Collins (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - The Ceded Strip, 1900 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - The Ceded Strip, 1901 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - The Ceded Strip, 1902 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - The Ceded Strip, 1903 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - The Ceded Strip – Altyn (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - The Ceded Strip – Blackfeet Indian Reservation (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - The Ceded Strip – Saint Mary's Early Formation (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - The Ceded Strip – Swift Current (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - The Ceded Strip – The Van Pelt Mine (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Central Montana Railroad (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Champoeg (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Charlie Buckley Murder – Robare (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Charlie Russell in Canada (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Charlie Russell on Shelby and McCarthyville (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Chinese Stories (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Choteau (Box 2, Folder 34-35)
  - Choteau – A.B. Hamilton (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Choteau – Acantha 4 part History (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Choteau Book – Society out in Montana (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Choteau – Business Firms (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Choteau County (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Choteau – Courthouse (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Choteau – Early Newspaper Ads (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Choteau – Historical Newspaper Stories, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Choteau – Items, 1885 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Choteau – Origin Story (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Choteau – Pete Turdo (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Cinnabar, Montana (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Clackamas, Clark County Boundaries (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Claude, Montana (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Collins, Montana (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Colstrip, Montana (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Concord, Montana (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Concord, Montana – School (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Conrad Montana (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Conrad centennial, October 2009 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Conrad – Flax Mill (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Conrad – Pondera Transition (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Conrad School Bonds, 1903 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - County Boundaries – Legislative sessions (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - County Info - General (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - County Maps from Waldron's book (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - County Material – Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - County Project – Continuing Projects (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - County Project – History of Washington Counties (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - County Project – Spokane county, Idaho counties (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - County Splitting – Dan McKay (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - County Splitting – Material (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Custer County (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Cypress Hills Massacre (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Dakota Territory – Early History (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Dakota Territory – Montana Politics (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Daniels County (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Dawson, Andrew (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Dawson County (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Dearborn County (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Deer lodge County (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Deer Lodge – Powell county – Museums (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Deer Lodge, Montana (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Denton, Montana (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Dr. Wine – Death Case (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Dumont, Gabriel (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Dunkirk, Montana (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Dupuyer, Montana (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Dupuyer – Acantha Pioneer Newspaper Story (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Dupuyer – All School Reunion, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Dupuyer – "And we buried Jim" Story (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - Dupuyer – Baseball (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Dupuyer – Beginning History (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - Dupuyer – Bill Jones Interview (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - Dupuyer – Blizzard, 1896 (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - Dupuyer – Book Filler (Box 2, Folder 91)
  - Dupuyer – Book Notes (Box 2, Folder 92-95)
  - Dupuyer – Brands (Box 2, Folder 96)
  - Dupuyer – Brick Factory (Box 2, Folder 97)
  - Dupuyer – Bridges (Box 2, Folder 98)
  - Dupuyer – Brother Van Orsdel Diary (Box 2, Folder 99)
  - Dupuyer – Buffalo (Box 2, Folder 100)
  - Dupuyer – Café Menu (Box 2, Folder 101)
  - Dupuyer – Catholic Church (Box 2, Folder 102)
  - Dupuyer – Catholic Church – Prando (Box 2, Folder 103)
  - Dupuyer – Reward Poster (Box 2, Folder 104)
  - Dupuyer – Cemetery (Box 2, Folder 105)
  - Dupuyer – Census, 1900 (Box 2, Folder 106)
  - Dupuyer – Census, 1910 (Box 2, Folder 107)
    School District 2
  - Dupuyer – Centennial Celebration (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Dupuyer – Centennial News Clips (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Dupuyer – Centennial Story, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Dupuyer – Coal Mines (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Dupuyer – County Proposed (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Dupuyer – Creek County (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Dupuyer – Creek Water Rights (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Dupuyer – Crees (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Dupuyer – Doctors (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Dupuyer – Early refinances (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Dupuyer – Families (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Dupuyer – Favorite photos (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Dupuyer – Fires (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Dupuyer – Founding stories (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Dupuyer – Grizzly Days, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Dupuyer – Grizzly Days, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Dupuyer – Grizzly Days, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Dupuyer – Grizzly Days, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Dupuyer – Grizzly Days, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Dupuyer – Grizzly Days, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Dupuyer – Grizzly Days, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Dupuyer – Highway 89 rebuild, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Dupuyer – Julian F. Burd (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Dupuyer – Linda Bruner Paper (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Dupuyer – List of Property Owners (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Dupuyer – Local Newspaper Clips, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Dupuyer – Lord Hill Material (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Dupuyer – Mandolin Society (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Dupuyer – Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 29-33)
  - Dupuyer – Mormon Trek through, in 1887 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Dupuyer – Murders (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Dupuyer – Mysteriarch Lodge (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Dupuyer – Name origins (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Dupuyer – News Article from "Travel and Leisure" (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Dupuyer – O.G. Cooper (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Dupuyer – Old-time Business (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Dupuyer – Organizations (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Dupuyer – Photos (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Dupuyer – Play, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Dupuyer – Political History (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Dupuyer – Polk Directories (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Dupuyer – Postmasters, Mail stories and Routes (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Dupuyer – Post Office (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Dupuyer – Railroad (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Dupuyer – Recollections of Early Days (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Dupuyer – Rodeo (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Dupuyer – Saloons (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Dupuyer – Sanborn Maps, 1914 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Dupuyer – School Board Controversy, 1903 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Dupuyer – School History Talk (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Dupuyer – School Material (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Dupuyer – School News Items (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Dupuyer – Stage Lines (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Dupuyer – Stories by Jack Hayne (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Dupuyer – Sun River, Sun Article, 1884 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Dupuyer – Traxler Story (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Dupuyer – Visitor and Travel Guide (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Dupuyer – "100 Years of Articles" (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Dutch Henry (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Dutton, Montana (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - Duvall, D.C. (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - Early Montana Survey (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - Early Pondera Industry – Coal and Brick (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - Early Pro Football story (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - Early territory/county divisions (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - Early Western explorer material (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - E.A. Savory (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - East Glacier - Miduale (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - Egg Cardling Story (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - Evolution of Montana Boundaries (Box 3, Folder 74)
  - Fairfield, Montana (Box 3, Folder 75)
  - Fallon County, Montana (Box 3, Folder 76)
  - Farm Bureau (Box 3, Folder 77)
  - Farmington, Montana (Box 3, Folder 78)
  - Faro – Chuck a Luck (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Fergus County (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - First Montana Map – Early legislation (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - Flathead County (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - Forest Grove, Montana (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - Fort Ashby – Willow Rounds (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - Fort Benton (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - Fort Benton, River Press, 1885 (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - Fort Benton – W.G. Conrad (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - Fort Conrad (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - Fort Conrad – Joe Kipp (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - Fort Ellis (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - Fort Hall (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - Fort Harrison (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - Fort MacKenzie (Box 3, Folder 93)
  - Fort Maginnis (Box 3, Folder 94)
  - Fort Peck Story (Box 3, Folder 95)
  - Fort Piegan on the Missouri (Box 3, Folder 96)
  - Fort Shaw (Box 3, Folder 97)
  - Fort Union (Box 3, Folder 98)
  - Fort Whoop-up (Box 3, Folder 99)
  - Fowler, Montana (Box 3, Folder 100)
  - Frizell – Mining (Box 3, Folder 101)
  - Froggies or Froggy's (Box 3, Folder 102)
  - Fur Trade (Box 3, Folder 103)
  - Fusee Gun – Needle Gun (Box 3, Folder 104)
  - Gallatin County, Montana (Box 3, Folder 105)
  - The Galloping Swede (Box 3, Folder 106)
  - Gallup City, Montana (Box 3, Folder 107)
  - Galt, Alexander, and Elliot (Box 3, Folder 108)
  - Garfield County, Montana (Box 3, Folder 109)
  - Garnett, Montana (Box 3, Folder 110)
  - Genou, Montana (Box 3, Folder 111)
  - Gilman, Montana (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - George Magee (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - George Steell (Box 4, Folder 3-5)
  - George Steell – Blackfeet Agency (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - George Steell – Diamond R (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - George Steell – The River Press (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - George Sturgeon (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Ghost Towns – Montana (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Glacier County, Montana (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Glacier County (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Glacier County – Pioneer Press (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Glacier Reporter – Blackfeet (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Golden Valley County, Montana (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Grain Elevators (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Granite County, Montana (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Gray's Harbor (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - The Great Blizzard, of 1898 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Great Falls – Steamboats (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - The Great Adventure (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Great Falls (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Grizzly Bears – Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Gundlatch, Montana (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Hangings (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Hardman, Oregon (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Hardrock Mining (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Hartford Townsite, Montana (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Haver, Montana (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Head Smashed In, Buffalo Jump (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Heritage Education (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Hell on Wheels (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Hitchcock Barn – Photos (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Highwood, Montana (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Hi-Line (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Hill County, Montana (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Hirshberg (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Hirshberg – Conrad (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Hirshberg – Fairfield (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Hirshberg – Lincoln Gulch – Cedar Creek (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Hirshberg – Robare Whiskey Trade (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Holy Family Mission – Fire (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Homestead Act Info (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Homestead Days – Impact on County Formation (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Horse Roundups, 1920-1935 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Horse Thieves – Dupuyer (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Hundred Governors Rule Montana for two Centuries (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Highway 89 – The Undiscovered Highway (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Idaho County Story (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Idaho Territory (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Idaho Territory – Organic Act (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Isaac Stevens Expedition (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Ivan Doig – Articles (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Ivan Doig – Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Ivan Doig – Ben English Claims (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - James Tufts (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Jefferson County, Montana (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Jerry Potts (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Jews on the Western Frontier (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Jimmy Grant (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Joe Connelly (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - John J. Hane (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - John Hayne – Grizzly Stories (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - John J. Healy (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - John Laughlin (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Joseph Kipp (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - Joesph Kipp – Water and Land Filings (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - Judith Basin County, Montana (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - Julian F. Burd – Story (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - Julian Burd – Independent Observer Article (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - Julian Burd – T.C. Powers Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - Julian Burd – Sheep Scheme, 1889 (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - J.W. McKnight (Box 4, Folder 73)
  - J.W. McKnight – Business Correspondence (Box 4, Folder 74)
  - Kanapsa Correspondent (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - Kendall, Montana (Box 4, Folder 76)
  - Kevin – Oilmont (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - Kootenai County (Box 4, Folder 78)
  - Koyl, Montana (Box 4, Folder 79)
  - The Klondike (Box 4, Folder 80)
  - Klondike Kate (Box 4, Folder 81)
  - Kremlin, Montana (Box 4, Folder 82)
  - Lake County, Montana (Box 4, Folder 83)
  - Laramie County – Dakota Territory, 1867 (Box 4, Folder 84)
  - Lewis and Clark County, Montana (Box 4, Folder 85)
  - Lewis and Clark Expedition (Box 4, Folder 86)
  - Lewis and Clark in Montana (Box 4, Folder 87)
  - Lewis and Clark Trail Council (Box 4, Folder 88)
  - Liberty County, Montana (Box 4, Folder 89)
  - Lincoln County, Montana (Box 4, Folder 90)
  - Little Plume Murder (Box 4, Folder 91)
  - Local Area Material (Box 4, Folder 92)
  - Local Area Trading Posts (Box 4, Folder 93)
  - Local Blackrobe Horse Trip, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 94)
  - Local Grizzly Stories (Box 4, Folder 95)
  - Local Maps Jack Reveal (Box 4, Folder 96)
  - Ledger, Montana (Box 4, Folder 97)
  - Leeson's History of Montana (Box 4, Folder 98)
  - Lehigh, Montana (Box 4, Folder 99)
  - Lincoln, Montana (Box 4, Folder 100)
  - Lohman, Montana (Box 4, Folder 101)
  - Lost Cabin Mine – Ceded Strip (Box 4, Folder 102)
  - Lovejoy, Montana (Box 4, Folder 103)
  - Louisiana Purchase – Info (Box 4, Folder 104)
  - Louis Riel (Box 4, Folder 105)
  - Madison County, Montana (Box 4, Folder 106)
  - Madison County – Mining Towns (Box 4, Folder 107)
  - Malcolm Clark (Box 4, Folder 108)
  - Father Mallman – Heart Butte (Box 4, Folder 109)
  - Many Glacier Lodge (Box 4, Folder 110)
  - Map of The West, 1846 (Box 4, Folder 111)
  - Maps of Montana, 1851 (Box 4, Folder 112)
  - Marshall, Bob (Box 4, Folder 113)
  - Marysvillie, Montana (Box 4, Folder 114)
  - McCarthyville, Montana (Box 4, Folder 115)
  - McCone County, Montana (Box 4, Folder 116)
  - McGregor, Washington (Box 4, Folder 117)
  - Meagher County – Diamond City (Box 4, Folder 118)
  - Meagher County, Montana (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Meagher County – Ghost Towns (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Medicine Wheel (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Meeker, Ezra (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Memorial Day (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Metis – Choteau (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Millegan, School (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Miner Courts and Government (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Mineral County, Montana (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Mining Towns – Early Day Montana (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Minutes of Shonkin Stock, 1881 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous County Project Info (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 5, Folder 13-14)
  - Missoula County, Montana (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Mixed Stories (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Moccasin, Montana (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Monarch, Montana (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Montana Album – Great falls tribune (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Montana Centennial Cattle Drive (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Montana Centennial (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Montana Centennial Newsletter (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Montana Council of Defense (Box 5, Folder 23)